<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Student Trainings | Peak Challenges</title>
    <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/</link>
      <atom:link href="/challenges/student_challenges_original/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Student Trainings</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hu03daf2b5ac51fd5e97da0fc2e3a0f1cd_98650_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Student Trainings</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginning Piano Lessons</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/110_activity_piano_lessons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/110_activity_piano_lessons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;20 minutes, live one-on-one lesson, once or twice weekly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You just need a keyboard!
&lt;em&gt;Total beginners and beginners with a bit of experience are welcome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you at home with a piano or keyboard just sitting over there in that room, with no one playing it? Are you thinking something like: “well, I have a lot of time, I COULD maybe learn how to play a little - or maybe a little more, if you’ve played in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is your chance! You can sign up for one or two 20 minute sessions weekly, one-on-one. You don’t need to already play piano, you don’t even need to have any music (at least to start).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll focus on having fun, with no stress. Times are flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/110_activity_piano_lessons.png&#34; alt=&#34;Piano Lessons Sketch&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Piano Lessons Fun&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chess</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/120_activity_chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/120_activity_chess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronous, using WhatsApp to share moves with standard algebraic notation &lt;em&gt;(e.g. Nxd5 - no worries if you don’t know what this is - super easy to learn)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp account to share moves with others. Open to beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that there is a loooooong history of chess being played across great distances? Check this out (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.chess.com/article/view/correspondence-chess---a-histo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;from chess.com&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A correspondence chess game between Emperor Nicephorus and the Caliph of Baghdad, Harun al-Rashid (763-809).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A correspondence chess game between King Henry I (1068-1135) of England and King Louis VI (1081-1137) of France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the 18th century, Frederick the Great (1712-1786) played a correspondence game with his early tutor, Voltaire (1694-1778), between Berlin and Paris.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1824, one of the first recorded games through the mail (like, paper letters and envelopes, that kind of mail) between the Amsterdam Rotterdam Chess Club.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s do it! We are not going to send a royal courier by horseback or send letters through the postal service, though. We’ll do it through a WhatsApp group. Hopefully this will work so well you’ll continue during the summer and then start up live again next fall in Leysin. We have plenty of chess boards and more than a few strong players out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algebraic_notation_%28chess%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;We’ll be using this notation to share moves&lt;/a&gt; - it’s easy, no worries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, beginners are welcome! You’ll get special tutoring, right from the very start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s your first lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;strong&gt;It’s not a horsey. It’s a knight!&lt;/strong&gt; And it moves like this: straight-straight-right, or straight-straight-left, or left-left- straight, or right-right-straight!&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games will be at prescribed times so that multiple moves - hopefully the complete game - can be played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/120_activity_chess_not_a_horsey.png&#34; alt=&#34;Chess Pieces&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chess Pieces (it&#39;s a knight -- NOT a horsey)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Writing</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/130_activity_creative_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/130_activity_creative_writing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shared Google docs, comments via the Google doc comment feature, group stats just for fun, products shared (with student permission) with LAS social media. Occasional group Google hangouts if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One great thing about creative writing is that you really can’t do anything wrong. It’s creative, so you create, and who is to say that any of that is wrong? Creative writing can also be in any language, or at least, any written language. That’s a huge advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, you can match what you are writing with what you are feeling. Feel happy? Write happy. Feel sad? Write sad. Feel energetic? Write a lot. You can make it fit you, you are in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/130_activity_creative_writing.png&#34; alt=&#34;Colorful Art - colors from a keyboard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Creativity at the keyboard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people find it hard to get writing. One way to start is to just start writing about whatever you are thinking of. Another way is to write on a subject that has been given you. Another way is to continue what someone else has started. There are more, many more, ways to get started. Most important is to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this all a bit of a game, we are going to challenge ourselves by doing two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;word-wham-challenge&#34;&gt;WORD Wham CHALLENGE&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll keep track of how many words we’ve written before going to bed Tuesday, and then from Wednesday before going to bed on Friday. Count (or estimate) the number of words you’ve written and enter them in the form for the week. We won’t keep track by individuals, but rather by how many words we write as a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;| Name           | Total Words (Mon) | Total Words (Thurs) | Week Total |
|                |                   |                     |            |
|                |                   |                     |            |
|                |                   |                     |            |
|                |                   |                     |            |
|                |                   |                     |            |
| TOTAL          |                   |                     |            |
| GRAND TOTAL    |                   |                     |            |

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share on your social media account - if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;excellent-excerpt-challenge&#34;&gt;Excellent Excerpt Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll also put our best paragraph, our best lines from a poem, or whatever we are working on (and what we select - “best” is subjective) in a doc to share. Just for fun. Our goal will be to get 100% of participants sharing their best excerpt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;| Name           | Favorite Quote               | Group Comments           |
|                |                              |                          |
|                |                              |                          |
|                |                              |                          |
|                |                              |                          |
|                |                              |                          |
| TOTAL          |                              |                          |
| GRAND TOTAL    |                              |                          |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll share the number of words (as a group) and perhaps some of the excerpts (if you give permission) with social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just for fun.  Feel free to participate in any language&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/140_activity_drawing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/140_activity_drawing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronous (or Asynchronous)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawings shared via Google Drive. Comments by participants to other participants shared via Google doc. Daily drawing challenge at this site. Live daily lesson at 14.00 Eastern time, 20.00 Swiss time, lessons also accessible at other times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None. Get a pencil, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you like to draw? Have you always thought you might like to draw better? Just want to have some fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An author and artist called JJ Krosoczka is doing a YouTube drawing or cartooning lesson every weekday at 14.00 (United States east coast; so 20.00 in Leysin, 21.00 in Moscow).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w8c608xOIFg&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/studiojjk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JJK YouTube Drawing Channel:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.studiojjk.com/draweveryday.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Studio JJK website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The live lessons might be fun to participate in, but you can also draw along write any of the recordings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If interested &amp;ndash; share your drawing on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Composting</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/150_activity_home_composting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/150_activity_home_composting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something fun and easy to build (after you’ve ordered the two basic materials) and something that you can continue experimenting with long after you’ve built it. It’s also a little easier on the environment, which all of us can appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will have to find or order coco peat, which is made from coconut husks, and kuntan, or rice husk ash, which is used widely in Japan to improve soil health. If you aren’t in Japan, no worries. The workaround is horticultural ash, e.g. hardwood ash. Ask in a garden store&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/06/climate/nyt-climate-newsletter-composting-coronavirus.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NYT article&lt;/a&gt; explains how you can make a simple compost bin that you can store right in your own home. The author claims it does not smell bad and that it doesn’t attract insects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Test his claim - make one and see what happens! Along the way you might find composting practical and enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The directions from the article come from a source in Japanese. Bonus! Learn composting and tell your friends you did it in Japanese. This will impress everyone, unless, of course, you are Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are just the pictures from the original 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.city.nagoya.jp/kankyo/page/0000060262.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nagoya City Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/150_activity_home_composting.png&#34; alt=&#34;Images of Home Coposting&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Home Composting&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Illustrated Maps</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/160_activity_illustrated_maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/160_activity_illustrated_maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous, drawings and peer comments shared via Padlet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None. Get a pencil, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/26/travel/how-to-make-an-illustrated-map-in-8-steps.html?smid=em-share&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Illustrated Map Making in 8 Steps - NY Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/160_activity_illustrated_maps.png&#34; alt=&#34;Images from Illustrated Maps Article&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Illustrated Maps Image from NY Times Article&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a nice twist on maps. Follow these eight steps to depict one of your favorite areas. Have fun with it, be creative, don’t be hard on yourself, and then share it with others at home and online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suggestions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area where your school or home is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A favorite vacation spot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A famous city you’d like to visit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The setting of one of your favorite books (use your imagination)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNaturalist</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/170_activity_i_naturalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/170_activity_i_naturalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous, using the app iNaturalist. You take pictures, identify the flora and fauna (plants and animals) in your immediate area, and add to the worldwide database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inaturalist.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;iNaturalist App&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; Free and open to all on the &lt;strong&gt;Apple AppStore&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iNaturalist is a fabulous app that lets you tell the world what plant and animal species live in your neighborhood (and wherever you travel). Using this app makes you a citizen scientist helping to discover the mysteries of this world. You can also use the app to learn the names of things for your own enjoyment - or to impress your friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might set yourself a goal of a set number of observations each day. Record any “natural” life forms you find (not your pets, friends, or houseplants). You can start on your own balcony, move to your yard, then your city block or a nearby park. It’s all useful to scientists trying to understand which species live where and how their distribution is changing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doing&#34;&gt;DOING:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notice&lt;/strong&gt; what is around you … &lt;strong&gt;Take a photo&lt;/strong&gt; … and &lt;strong&gt;upload&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! If there are a number of students joining this activity in the same week, you may be placed in a group so you can see how many observations others are making at the same time - and of what kinds of plants and animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/170_activity_i_naturalist.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image of iNaturalist Website&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Image of iNaturalist Website&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore with DuoLingo</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/180_activity_duolingo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/180_activity_duolingo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous, using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.duolingo.com&#34;&gt;www.duolingo.com&lt;/a&gt; (free version just fine). Contact Paul Magnuson (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:pmagnuson@las.ch&#34;&gt;pmagnuson@las.ch&lt;/a&gt;) or text +41-79-376-4765 when you begin and you’ll be put in a group of everyone else using Duolingo. Consider combining this activity with Touch Typing for a helpful hack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/180_activity_duolingo.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image of DuoLingo&#39;s Mascot&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;DuoLingo Mascot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duolingo.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DuoLingo App&lt;/a&gt; - available on &lt;strong&gt;Apple AppStore&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Google PlayStore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duolingo is the most successful, in terms of the number of users anyway, educational app in history. There are lots of languages - French, German, Portuguese, and Spanish have the most features, but don’t let that stop you from checking out any of the languages offered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want a real challenge? Work in two languages that aren’t your native tongue. For example, if you know some French but little Italian, try some Italian lessons in French.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out the stories (in the four languages mentioned above). There are also high quality podcasts in French and Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Composition</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/190_activity_music_composition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/190_activity_music_composition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous, written music shared via email attachment, music shared by sound files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least some piano playing ability, which will give you just enough background knowledge of music theory to get started. Occasional group hangouts if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/190_activity_music_composition.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image of Musical Notation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Musical Notation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever made up a song on the piano and wanted to write it down? Instead of always playing things that other people wrote, would you like to play something that you wrote?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During spring break, I started writing very short piano pieces - nothing longer than 16 measures. I found out you can make a really satisfying song in 16 measures. It doesn’t take too long, it’s fun, there is no right or wrong, you can experiment with different sounds and styles … what’s not to like about that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture is an example of a song begun this April by a beginning piano player. Depending on how much you know about music, you’ll see that she has a unique first measure, in common time, key of C, that goes to a IV chord in the second measure, then a V, resolved in measure three with the tonic. She doesn’t know any of that terminology - she just wrote what sounded good to her, by herself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where you will start, too. If by chance you do have some music theory in your background, you can bring that into play, too. Why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know much about musical notation, I’ll help you out. All you need is at least a little knowledge of the piano, a little bit of interest, and some paper lined like the example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is a small group of us, we’ll share what we’ve written (in notation, sound files, or both) and who knows … maybe we’ll have a short online recital in May.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scavenger Hunt</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/200_activity_scavenger_hunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/200_activity_scavenger_hunt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronous activity, through Google Hangout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time (or times) for the Scavenger Hunt(s) will be set up according to where you are in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact Paul Magnuson (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:pmagnuson@las.ch&#34;&gt;pmagnuson@las.ch&lt;/a&gt;) to sign up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This activity is just for fun, nothing else. No other agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scavenger hunt at summer camp usually works like this: each team of players gets a list of items that they need to find. At a camp out in the woods there might be some things from the woods (a pine cone - easy!; a bird’s nest - harder!) or some things that players might have brought with them to the camp (e.g. a coin from South America or a size 42 tennis shoe).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. Here how this is going to work online. Every player gets on a Google Hangout at the same time. Players are going to find the items of the scavenger hunt in their own homes. The first person to return to the Google hangout with the item gets the most points. Every three minutes a new item is listed and players can search for that item for more points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POINTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 points - First person with the item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 points - Second person with the item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 points - Third person with the item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 points - Fourth person with the item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 point   - Fifth person with the item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it’s a race - with some chance built in, but some reward for the fleetest of foot (be fast).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples of items you might be looking for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a family photo with 4 generations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leftovers from the refrigerator in a plastic container&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;an School Yearbook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;socks with holes in the heels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get the idea. Just for fun! See you online with the list of items to find.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Portrait Triptych</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/210_activity_self_portrait_triptych/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/210_activity_self_portrait_triptych/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synchronous (or Asynchronous)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawings shared via Google Drive. Comments by participants to other participants shared via Google doc. Daily drawing challenge at this site. Live daily lesson at 14.00 Eastern time, 20.00 Swiss time, lessons also accessible at other times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None. Get a pencil, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A triptych is a painting, actually three paintings, displayed on three connected panels. Here are 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drawpaintacademy.com/triptych/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Triptych examples&lt;/a&gt; as well as more background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fifteen minutes, you are going to make your own triptych, out of your own image. You can use a pencil, or pens, whatever you prefer. There are three rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must draw your face, three times, each with a wildly different expression.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must be looking in a mirror the entire time you are drawing - you cannot look at the paper itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must finish each picture within five minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 15 minutes, you have three self-portraits, with three different expressions, all a bit Picasso like because you NEVER looked at the paper while you were drawing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/210_activity_self_portrait_tritych.png&#34; alt=&#34;Triptych Art Example&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Triptych Art Example&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Directed Language Learning</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/220_activity_language_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/220_activity_language_learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Tools in this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/28/travel/language-instruction-apps-television-youtube.html?referringSource=articleShare&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;New York Times article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, I led a year-long language course for students ages 15-19 to learn any language they wanted, in any manner they wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest takeaway? Most students were not very good at managing their own learning. They had trouble staying motivated, they had trouble picking one focus and sticking to it, and they had difficulty taking the time to really figure out their own way to go about learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, students in the last years of high school were not very good learners when there wasn’t a teacher telling them what to do, almost every step of the way. YIKES.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So. Give yourself a gut check. See how independent a learner you are. Here’s the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read this 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/28/travel/language-instruction-apps-television-youtube.html?referringSource=articleShare&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NY Times article on language learning&lt;/a&gt;: In a short paragraph, describe:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you are going to learn;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What your learning process (and resources) will be;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much time you are going to commit for 5 days in a row; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much you think you will be able to accomplish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share that info with me on Day 1. At the end of Day 5, reflect on your experience. Consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What happened to your self-motivation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did you accomplish your learning - what things that you did helped you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tended to derail your learning? When did learning fall apart?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is one thing you could do NOW to become a better self-regulated learning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share that reflection with me, too. I will comment back on all submissions. Depending on the number and quality of reflections, you may be invited to a group discussion as a follow-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/220_activity_language_learning.png&#34; alt=&#34;Colorful Art - colors from a keyboard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Credit: Elenia Beretta, from the NYT article in the links above&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touch Typing</title>
      <link>/challenges/student_challenges_original/230_activity_touch_typing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/challenges/student_challenges_original/230_activity_touch_typing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;committment&#34;&gt;Committment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous, self-tracking and short check-ins with the activity leader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisite&#34;&gt;Prerequisite&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typingclub.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.typingclub.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;the free version also works just fine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;activity&#34;&gt;Activity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, Paul, had two quarters of typing class in high school. At the time, we learned on typewriters - big ones called 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBM_Selectric_typewriter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IBM Selectrics&lt;/a&gt;. It was the most valuable class in my high school career. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s no way I can add up the amount I have typed since I went to college. It’s a lot. In the nearly 40 years since I hauled my own typewriter to my new dorm room I’ve spent maaaany hours writing. Email volume now is so high that I can’t imagine getting through it without being able to type quickly.
So what do you need to do in this activity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/img/trainings/students/230_activity_touch_typing.png&#34; alt=&#34;Colorful Art - colors from a keyboard&#34;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Credit: Elenia Beretta, from the NYT article in the links above&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typingclub.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.typingclub.com&lt;/a&gt; and start practicing. The lessons walk you through what to do and how to develop good habits. You’ll find that after just a few hours you have the hang of it - after that, more practice adds up to more speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep track of your average speed. If you are only trying this for a week, then commit to some practice every day. At the end of the day write down your average speed. See if you can make that average speed climb by the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make it through that first week and continue, keep track of your average speed by week. Commit to a Friday morning test, for example, every week. And … to help yourself stick to one of the most valuable courses you could ever hack, combine touch typing (and speedy touch typing) with another activity. For me that is Duolingo. Try that combination out if you like - or discover your own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
