<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trust | Peak Challenges</title>
    <link>/tag/trust/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/trust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>trust</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 16:39:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_huecd22494e7b526781a22a605648a9ace_13089_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>trust</title>
      <link>/tag/trust/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultivating Trust between Administration and Faculty</title>
      <link>/blog/edgility_admin_faculty_trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 16:39:12 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/edgility_admin_faculty_trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was reminded again recently of how important trust is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve been working for more than a few years now to move from a traditional A-F, 100-0 percent American grading system to a 1-7 standards based system. There are still a few kinks in the system, from how the grade reporting software works to how we as teachers understand and use the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our point person for assessment is very aware of the need for trust. He included this reminder in a recent document listing the status of issues we have left to finalize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A word about trust: In order to deal with the issues all faculty will need to be involved. One key ongoing point that can be a barrier to progress is the fear of hurt feelings - issues are not raised at appropriate times leading to greater problems down the line. The general feeling is that people would rather be told there is an issue and be given the support to correct it than to be protected by the bubble, unsure if the issues they here discussed are actually because of them. In order to progress we need a system of support that is just that - supportive and not punitive. Staff should feel that making mistakes is not a criticism, it is just something that has happened and the sooner it is addressed the better. This applies across every single area of the school, in every department and at every level. Nobody wants to be ‘that one person who…’ but neither do they want to work day to day with the nagging feeling that they don’t get it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get better, to improve, we need to trust each other. We have to be okay with a bit of vulnerability. We have to ask questions about what we don’t understand. We’re well served by nodding yes only when &lt;em&gt;we really get it&lt;/em&gt;. All of this comes from working on culture and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because you can’t simply tell people they need to trust more. It doesn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People - the work group, the school, the community - need to experience trust, feel trust, and believe in trust because trust is there. This is culture - and it is why agilists stress people and relationships, and why they remind each other and those they train that it is about creating a culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suppose if there’s a need to remind folks about trust, like our assessment leader did, there is probably room to work on the level of trust in the school culture. We also suppose that there is always a need to work on trust in the school culture. This is what Bill understood long before the rest of us, and why EDgility presents its principles in terms of practices. A practice is something you get better at by doing it. So you have to constantly do it, increasing your ability over time. You strive to shift a little in the direction you want to be more like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A phenomenal teacher trainer I worked with at the University of Minnesota used to remind us that teachers won’t likely change their practices until they see results they believe in … as a result of their changed practices! This is of course a Catch 22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that thought in mind, we can imagine just how fragile trust is. It comes in little, uncoordinated events, through shared experiences, by noticing its positive effects. And it can be damaged very quickly. Hence it is a practice which requires constant attention, whether through a gentle reminder to everyone, like our example above, or the shared awareness of a community of people who value trust, and therefore cultivate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the desire to cultivate trust becomes part of the culture, teachers can more easily share that trust with their students by allowing self-regulation over carrot and stick control. In other words, when there is a chance, encourage a bit more self-regulation. Model it and make it a practice of yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploration in the Classroom</title>
      <link>/blog/edgility_classroom_exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 16:57:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/blog/edgility_classroom_exploration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fun and a sense of adventure can be crucial to classroom engagement and learning. Cultivating a sense of adventure is similar to encouraging an atmosphere of playfulness and joy of learning. This can be quite straightforward when students are allowed to create their own goals and their own context for the goals within the curriculum. Of course, any good adventure can’t be too easy. It’s the teacher’s job to make sure a project has no obvious, googleable answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We might worry that making the project hard and beyond what the students know how to do could be unfair or even unjust. This might be true. When students are used to the mindset of getting things right the first time, it is difficult for them to take an idea and ‘play’ with it until something works. This adjustment takes some time, but once they get the hang of it, students enjoy exploring and they learn quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I most enjoy  observing how students learn resilience through ‘playing’ with ideas and trying different options until they find a solution. In fact, in today’s world it may be more important to learn resilience, persistence, and finding the next small workable step in order to progress toward a goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course creating an environment where exploration can thrive requires not doing a few things, too - such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging or criticizing mistakes or rework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not judging the work or its qualities, instead let the kids cultivate their own pride and ownership (the minimum quality tests need clear, objective and observable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not celebrating the answers, but celebrating the exploratory and learning aspects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not requiring that every student have the same depth of knowledge in each part of the project. It&amp;rsquo;s important to define baseline knowledge they all need to have - but after that they need to be free to explore more deeply what the student finds interesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To encourage exploration we have found that the following the guidance for a growth mindset is very helpful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Praise the grit and perseverance of arriving at a workable solution;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cultivate the mindset of finding the next workable thing to try, even when there is no clear path to the goal; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage / expect (maybe even require) rework and changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a practical note, it is important to create projects that are complex and have some built-in conflict that requires balancing and tradeoffs. This is important for several reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without trade-offs, a problem isn’t realistic and can be too easily googled.  The problem must be challenging enough or it isn’t engaging (but it needs to be workable).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having to resolve a conflict or resolve tradeoffs and still arrive at one&amp;rsquo;s goals requires students to really go into depth and learn that aspect extra well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE:&lt;/strong&gt; In the world of engineering, it is important to have a solid generalist understanding of the field (like the basic required information tested at school), but that is rarely enough for most teams. It is important to be a specialist in at least one area of interest &amp;ndash; these are called ‘T’ shaped engineers - engineers that have gone deep into two areas are even more valuable and are called ‘π’ shaped engineers. I’m advocating for creating projects (and classroom environments) in school that cultivate the same generalist / specialist mindset that is often expected in graduate school and professional lives. Art curriculums have long taught the core skills and ideas and then expected students to explore and expand upon their interests. Imagine how engaging education could be when all aspects of schools encouraged choice and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching this way can be uncomfortable for teachers who may traditionally have felt that they need to operate as the expert who knows everything. To model the idea, however, that you don’t have to know everything, it is actually helpful not to know everything. In fact, you cannot give students a quick answer, which cuts off their chance to think through the problem, and instead you explore with the students and model how to learn and resolve difficult problems. The teacher must simply understand the basics and vocabulary of the field to help students interpret what they find.  Of course the teacher must also be comfortable modeling exploring the unknown with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
